在这个讲座中，我们将讨论颜色。你可能会仔细地注意到我
In this lecture we're going to talk about color. You probably notice that I studiously
到目前为止避免谈论颜色。这个讲座我们将正确谈论颜色。
avoided talking about color so far. This lecture we're going to talk properly about color.
颜色对动物来说非常重要。几乎所有看到的动物都可以
Color is something that's really important for animals. Almost all animals that see can
在某种程度上看到颜色。
see color to some extent.
如果你想一想我们祖先的觅食，也许颜色很重要的一个原因
And perhaps one reason why color is important, if you think about our ancestors' foraging
对于食物而言，或许重要的是能够在背景中检测到一些红色水果
for food, perhaps it was important to be able to detect some red fruits against the background
一棵绿树。所以在这个讲座中，我们将讨论什么颜色，它在哪里
of a green tree. So in this lecture we're going to talk about what color is, where it
来自我们如何处理计算机中的彩色图像。到目前为止我们一直都是
comes from and how we can deal with color images in the computer. So far we've been
处理灰度图像。我们如何编写计算机程序来确定
dealing with gray scale images. And how we can write the computer program to determine
一些物体是什么颜色的。
what color some object is.